# Michael Wheeler

## Lead Software Developer

michael.wheeler856@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Software developer with varied experience working in small, cross-functional teams through the full application lifecycle. Projects include data pipelines, web and desktop applications and test automation frameworks. Focus on testing and fast reliable deployment via CI/CD pipelines.

## Experience

## Opia Limited, Newcastle upon Tyne

September 2019 - Present

### **Development Team Lead**

March 2021 - Present

Leading the internal product development team, responsibilities include the core event-driven microservice platform, supplier integrations with banks, recyclers and couriers and a base template for client sites. Team leader responsibilities included spreading development and agile best practices, training and managing developers and communicating with the wider business.

- PHP, MySQL, VueJS, Redis streams.
- DevOps Tools: Docker, Rancher, Jenkins, Rancher.

#### **Senior Software Developer**

September 2020 - March 2021

## **Software Developer**

September 2019 - September 2020

### MagenTys, an NTT DATA company, London

September 2018 - Present

## **Senior Application Software Development Consultant**

May 2019 - Present

Creation of a test automation framework for a large-scale digital transformation project, utilising REST API's to automate integration tests.

- Framework: C#, Ninject, Serilog.
- DevOps Tools: Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Bamboo, Azure, Artifactory.

September 2018 - May 2019

Building of ETL processes, performing data analysis and creation of data dashboards. A DataOps approach was used to ensure fast, scalable and reliable pipeline setup.

- Data Pipeline and Dashboarding: Python, Elasticsearch, Grafana, Pandas, Webhooks.
- DevOps Tools: AWS, Docker, Jenkins.

## MagenTys, London

October 2017 - September 2018

Project to replace till and back office hardware at a leading British retailer. Included creation, deployment and maintenance of several new applications as part of a cross-functional, agile team. DevOps best practices were implemented to manage, build and release automation.

- Desktop Applications: Java, Node.js (Electron), C# (WPF, ASP.NET), websockets.
- DevOps Tools: Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, Azure, Nuget, Nexus, Powershell and Bash Scripting.

## Qualifications

I have completed the Architecting on AWS course and plan to sit the Associate AWS Certified Solutions Architect exam.

## Education

**University of Warwick** - Physics MPhys, BSc (Upper Second Class)

Oct 2011 - Jun 2015

- Developed excellent problem-solving skills.
- Masters research project: X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy of Modified Semiconductor Surfaces.
- Won a grant of £2700 from the Lord Rootes Memorial Fund to complete a solo 5,000km bike tour across Europe.